let's look at the answer to our spatial
locality quiz the question is which
memory locations have spatial locality
remember that spatial locality says that
once we access the memory location we
are likely to access nearby memory
locations soon for the variable J we
keep pre accessing J but we don't know
what's close to J so we cannot really
say that J has spatial locality if we
access J there is a lot of temporal
locality but not necessarily any spatial
locality same for some we are accessing
some very often by itself but we are not
really sure whether we are accessing
anything that is close to some four
elements of array R we have seen that
there is no temporal locality each
element is accessed only once in this
loop however there is a lot of spatial
locality once we access R of 0 in the
next iteration we will be accessing R of
1 and then R of 2 and so on so it is
true that once we access a memory
location in this array we are likely to
access nearby locations soon so this
variable definitely has spatial locality
it turns out that the way this program
is compiled usually means that there
will be some spatial locality between J
and some J and some are likely to be
allocated by the compiler on the stack
near each other so when we access some
and then access J that might be an
example of spatial locality